Looks like we got some more people coming in right now.
Welcome, welcome, Ryan. Can you hear me?
Yeah, I can. I'm, I'm in a bit of a loud location,
so I'll probably stay on mute, but I can hear
Amazing. Where you at?
Uh, eating a late breakfast.
Late breakfast, I mean, 10. Where are you at?
Are you in East Coast or, uh,
Phoenix. So it's
11. Oh yeah. Not terribly late.
Just, I usually, usually eat much earlier,
but I was doing a bunch of work this morning
and I was like, if I don't eat now, I'm not gonna feel good.
I hear you, dude. I'll get that, that stomach cramp
and then I just get hangry. I just
Get, yeah, I, I need a lot of calories in the morning.
My brother does this, you know, like, uh,
intermittent fasted thing where he doesn't eat
until a late lunch
to limit his calorie and take during the day.
But I, it's not for me. I,
I gotta get calories in earlier. It's bad day.
Yeah, I, I've done it both.
I've done the intermittent fasting for a minute.
Um, it works if you're like, intentionally trying
to lose weight, but I'm a,
No, I just don't feel good.
I mean, I could do it one or two days, but,
Um, amazing dude.
How's everyone else doing? What's up? Sparse Asim?
Nah, you chan. Is that how I pronounce it? How's it going?
It's going good, man. Are you in the stars right now?
You in, what galaxy are you in?
I was just trying to play with Zoom a little bit today.
Yeah, dude, I love it. We should just change our backdrops
to, uh, different galaxies.
Um, awesome, awesome.
We'll give it a couple more minutes, see if, uh,
we can get more people to jump on.
Um, but in the meantime, um,
excited for everybody here.
Thank you for joining in.
Uh, I don't know if anybody here celebrates Thanksgiving,
anybody outside us?
Obviously not, but, um,
anybody do any like Black Friday stuff?
Black Friday pushes, promos, edits sales,
because it was, it's been,
it's been one hell of a week for us.
It may have been more of a,
a consumer than producer of this. That's not good.
Well, yeah, like, did anybody take any, get any deals?
Take advantage?
Yeah, I, I did get a bunch of random, uh, random stuff.
I know. It's like my, um, it's funny
'cause my wife, she was like, she's like, oh,
they just released like this new DJ I camera thing.
And, uh, it like, it's really cool. It's, it's neat.
She's like, oh babe,
this would be real nice for, for Hawaii.
And I'm like, I'm like, we're not, what are you gonna use?
Are you gonna be a vlogger now?
Um, you know, and it's just, just
because the deal's out, you're like, oh,
maybe I can use this now.
It's just, I'm sure.
I'm sure there's a psychology behind that, Billy.
I know, I know. You know, I had quite a few of those.
And just in case purchases, eh, just in case I'm gonna go
to Hawaii and need, need a, a GoPro
for snorkeling just in case.
Yeah, exactly. And you'll use it one time
and then just keep it in a, keep it in a drawer.
Yeah. Um, exactly. I love it. I love it. What's up Ralston?
Long time. No, see
bud. Awesome.
B speeds. So Ralston actually, uh,
purchased your course, Billy, so seeing Yeah, I know.
Roston. Hey, good to see you, Roston.
Have you guys met before?
No, we haven't. We haven't. I know your name now.
Yes, exactly. It's awesome, man. Good to have you.
Thank you. Looking forward.
Likewise, likewise. Um, it was funny actually.
We'll, we'll get started in probably like two more minutes
and then just kinda let people trickle in.
Um, it's funny, I, uh, actually is anybody here
who hasn't heard of Billy?
Um, raise your hand in the chat.
It's your first time. One
Work. I hadn't heard of
Billy before,
but I actually got introduced to you, Billy
through Johns and John's course.
Sweet. The light, the light light,
the five light bulbs framework. So
Love to hear that. Thank you, John. Yeah,
You, You're gonna have
to cohost this thing with me, Roston.
I mean, you've been through the program,
you're gonna have to step up.
Yeah, dude, you, you know,
more than I do at this point, Ralston, so Yeah,
Not at all. Not at
all. All learning together.
Yeah. No, I'm, I'm, I'm really excited.
Um, I actually found Billy through another workshop, um,
via Vidal.
Um, and that just kinda like blew my mind in terms of, uh,
what he went over as an agency.
Creative, creative business owner, um, you know,
managing different employees
and having all these different processes.
Billy really found a way to distill very, like
unorganized, uh, ways of doing product research,
customer research, angle research,
and distilled it into a very like, simple five step formula.
And, um, I'm super excited to have him here.
He's someone that I definitely look up to in the space.
Um, he's accomplished a lot
and he has, um, an amazing brain, um,
thinks like a programmer, um, writes like a poet.
And, um, and I'm just super stoked to have him here.
So, welcome Billy.
My wife would disagree on the brain comment,
but thank you, John.
I'm person in the world.
Um, but I appreciate the, uh, the kind intro. Yeah.
You know, and, uh, and that's cool.
Yeah, that, um, that we bumped into each other over in vid
ow where they do a lot of YouTube advertising.
It's such a great lesson for all of us too, right?
Because I mean, that's YouTube, that's YouTube ads.
This is e-commerce focused.
I've done a lot of stuff with the creator crowd,
with the expert crowd coaches online courses
and things, you know, bringing the five lightposts
to all these different markets, so, uh, in industries.
So it's just such a good lesson for all
of us about messaging and
'cause we get so caught up in the tactics and the technology
and the platforms and everything,
but messaging is platform agnostic.
It's, uh, it's medium agnostic.
I mean, I'm, I'm a write writing first kind of guy,
but like, you know, you mentioned OW
and YouTube videos, right?
Like, you need a script, right? And you,
and you write those scripts.
So it's just a good way for us to think about marketing
and, you know, taking a step back from like,
boots on the ground, tactics, channels, all that stuff.
And just thinking, okay, well at the end of the day,
what are we saying?
And I always say, when you, I always say, right,
when you change your words, you change your results.
And, and that was the big thing for me.
I mean, so a little bit of my backstory,
I came from the engineering world
and then, uh, wanted to do my own thing.
So I launched a beer brewing course
'cause I was really into brewing beer at the time,
being fresh outta college.
And, uh, and so started selling online courses in,
uh, the beer brewing space.
So like, very like niche online course space.
That's where I was. And, uh,
and just realized that copywriting was the
big thing that I was missing.
I mean, despite having this fancy business degree, none of
that was helping me sell my $47 beer brewing course.
And yeah. And, and I got so overwhelmed too.
I mean, you guys probably feel the same way.
Uh, I know you feel the same way, right?
Like all the tools and like the, it,
it just sucks your time, doesn't it?
All the things that you don't expect
to suck your time when it comes to online marketing.
I just, I remember just filling with like logos
and, uh, my WordPress plugins and all that stuff, and,
and I realized like that that really, like, you have
to factor in that the cost of that time.
And I would much rather just rewrite a headline than install
a new plugin that's probably gonna break on
me or get hacked or something.
So, you know, I'm always, I think it's
that engineering background where I'm always looking
for leverage and like, what's the small
touch that can move a mountain?
And for me, that's just changing the words.
So it's like, let's start with that.
And then once we dial that in as much as possible, then
focus on eking out those extra gains through the tactics
and the channels and the plugins and, and all that stuff.
So that's a little bit about how I, I think about things.
It's, it's always in terms of leverage.
Uh, what's the smallest input for the largest output?
And then that really led to the five light bulbs,
which I'm excited to introduce you all to.
Uh, it's one of those things. It's, so,
it's a messaging framework.
There's not a whole lot of those out there.
Probably the closest thing to it is StoryBrand,
if you're familiar with Donald Miller and, and StoryBrand.
Uh, so it's a framework, it's a model, it's a mold.
You can, you can pour your raw, raw ingredients into it
and it'll spit out your marketing assets, which we all need.
So websites, landing pages, emails, ads, all those things.
Videos, right?
So, uh, you can think about
what we're gonna do here, and we are gonna walk through this.
This will be very interactive.
Uh, I don't know if John told you guys,
but have something to draw with.
Ideally, bring some color to the table.
We wanna make this fun. So color, pencils, crayons,
whatever you got, borrow 'em from your kids.
Just make sure to give 'em back.
And we're gonna walk through the five light bulbs
and, uh, and, and get an idea.
I mean, we don't have a ton of time here, but we'll get an
idea out of what your core message is.
And then, uh,
and then that, I really look at that as kind
of like a brand manual, but instead of having the logos
and the fonts and the colors
and all that stuff, which is important,
but let's be honest with what we do, it's not as important
as conversions and the words that you use
and your persuasive messaging.
So this worksheet that you're gonna create on your piece
of paper in front of you, uh, you can think about that
as like your brand manual,
but for your persuasive messaging.
So we ready to dive into it? Cool.
Let's do it. Can I get a thumbs up in the group?
Anyone falling along? Did anyone fall asleep already?
Just kidding. There we go. I like, like seeing those emojis.
All right. Yeah, I think if you just put your thumbs up
on the screen, does it work?
No, I guess it, no it doesn't. That's stupid.
Don't even do that. Would it recognize it?
That's coming, that's in the next Zoom update.
Yeah, that's the Exactly Zoom 2059. All right.
Yeah, by all means, Billy.
Um, feel free to share your screen
and we'll, yeah, we'll, we'll dive into it.
So we're going, so I'm gonna hop back and forth.
I got a more formal presentation so you can see.
I, um, I'm a very visual thinker
and I, I think a lot of people are,
especially in marketing, I find that's really common.
Um, the problem is I suck at drawing.
So I, as you're gonna see, so I hired a,
a really great illustrator and he created this whole world.
It's kinda like the Marvel universe
for the five light bulbs.
Ralston's seen it. And, uh, so I'm gonna show that
to describe each of the five light bulbs.
But then we're gonna hop over to the, the worksheet for me,
it'll be in Miro, and
I'll draw the thing along with you guys.
But first, let's get into it here.
Love that logo, by the way, John. Okay.
So first, the overview. Here are the five light bulbs.
You can see this world that we created.
We have a bear, we have an owl.
Uh, I'll explain the, the symbolism behind them when we get
to light bulb two.
But to run through 'em real quick, we have light bulb one,
which is your customer status quo, light bulb.
Two, the things that the customers tried
before to solve their problem.
Light bulb three, that's an interesting one.
That's your approach, not your product, but your approach.
We'll talk more about that. Light bulb four, your offer.
That includes your product, but it's not just your product.
We'll get more into that. And light bulb five,
the customer's new life.
So you've probably seen this metaphor
before, this bridge metaphor,
but it's kind of like that on steroids.
And, um, and, and what I did is I really went back to a lot
of the old copywriters, especially this guy.
If you look at my camera, you know, Eugene Schwartz
and his book Breakthrough Advertising.
Has anybody read this? It's a,
it's a really phenomenal book.
Uh, unfortunately it's like $500 on Amazon.
'cause it, it went outta print.
And, uh, I think I paid a hundred bucks for it. I got lucky.
And, uh, and, and so it, it's dense,
but he has such powerful stuff in there.
But a lot of it hasn't seen the light of day.
'cause just not a lot of people have bought the book,
let alone, like, implemented it, studied it,
let alone taught it, right?
Like the people who really do know this stuff are
hardcore copywriters in their basement, making a killing,
but not teaching this stuff.
And I'm very much a teacher.
So the five lip pops, like, it looks almost childish.
It's very simple, it's playful,
but just know that there is, there are very powerful
and advanced copywriting concepts that have gotten into it.
So that's a big thing I'm trying
to do is take what's in this book
and put it into this simple package for people.
Okay, so let's get into it. Light bulb one. All right.
Type in the chat. What words come
to mind when you look at this illustration?
Lemme pull up the chat here. Yeah. Raining and death. Yeah.
Not gloomy, huh? Hopelessness pain. Bleak.
Yeah, I like that word ton. Yeah. Bleak, negative.
Notice the, uh, the vulture up here.
What does that symbolize? Why does a vulture show up?
Yeah, the burned trees. Yeah, exactly, John. Yeah.
So you can think about it that like,
your customer has been burned in the past,
so you gotta factor these things in.
You gotta think about this. So lipo one is the language
of empathy.
It's, it's giving voice to where your customer is right now.
Yeah, like that you're about to get eaten. Yeah.
A sense of foreboding, right? Like, things might get worse.
And is that true for your customers too?
Might things get worse if they don't solve their problem?
Yeah. Yeah.
And so you wanna give voice to that and,
and not in like, um, a manipulative way,
because marketing is one of those things
where it's very powerful and like, like anything
that's powerful, like status, like a gun,
it can be used for good or for evil.
So you don't wanna, you, you wanna be empathetic, um,
but you don't wanna do it in a manipulative way
where you're like, Hey, if you don't solve this problem,
like you're so screwed.
You wanna treat it more like, um,
like a doctor would treat a patient like, Hey,
if you don't solve this problem,
this is what typically happens.
This is what I've seen in my experience. Okay?
So this should be on the website, this type of language,
the word you, we often go to websites, and it's not that.
It's, it's wee wee. We, I, I, I. This is how great we are.
We've won all these awards.
So let's hop on over here
and we're gonna draw this together.
So I, I want you to get some bullet points down
for your light bulb one.
Okay? So now we get into the, the crappy drawing,
not the nice illustration here.
So I'm gonna pick a color here. We're gonna draw that chasm.
So the one that you saw in that first illustration
with all the five light bulbs, we're gonna draw that.
So I'm gonna draw a cliff over here, go down,
and I'm gonna draw the other one over here
to create this gap over and down.
There we go. And then pick your favorite color
and draw your customer the bear.
It's all used blue. And you saw that scene.
I mean, that is a gnarly place that the customer is in.
So they, they shouldn't look too happy.
So I'm gonna draw our prospect here.
And they're very frustrated, right?
So they got their hands on their hips here.
They've been burned before, right?
So that, that's where they are right now.
Uh, gimme a thumbs up when you've gotten this far.
Okay, cool. Great. Okay.
Now draw a light bulb
over this side, over this cliff.
You can put it right behind your prospect here.
And light bulb one, the name of this one is the status quo.
Status quo. Where, where things that are the same, it's the,
we often call this the unacceptable status quo.
So you might wanna write that down.
The unacceptable status quo.
And again, you want to give voice to this.
So this should not just wind up
as bullet points on a worksheet.
The idea is that this winds up on your sales pages,
in your ads, uh, on your product pages,
your product descriptions, emails.
Okay? So now take a couple minutes here.
Uh, I will even in, I'll play some music.
I got some good workshop and music here.
Take a couple minutes and,
and just get this down for yourself.
I really want you to walk away from this,
not just have watched a presentation, but have,
but have, uh, gotten work done.
So take a couple minutes and I want you to get, uh,
a couple bullets down for light bulb one,
and I'll type this into the chat.
So, light bulb one,
what is their status quo?
What is the problem they are facing?
Okay? So take a couple minutes, get as much down as you can.
Any ideas for light bulb, one words, phrases,
and then we will come back and move on to light bulb.
Two
quick question.
Maybe I missed it, Billy. Um, who are we referring to?
Um, in terms of the, the person or customer?
Oh, you're, you're muted. Sorry about that.
Your customer avatar, your main one.
So if you have multiple customer avatars, okay,
this works better when you're very specific
with that, so, got it.
Pick one and, uh, yeah, enroll with that one
for the rest of the workshop.
Okay, cool, cool. Yeah.
So everybody here is involved in different niches
and stuff, so, um, yeah.
Focus on the one that you know best for the exercise.
Exactly, yeah. And I mean, if there's a new one
that you want to target, maybe then that,
that could be a good use of this time too.
Okay. Yeah. We'll just take one or two minutes here.
Okay. How did that go? You get some ideas down?
Yeah. Cool. Yeah, that's an important one.
There's this, uh, I love copywriting,
I love studying the old copywriters.
And there's this famous phrase in copywriting where,
lemme know if you've heard this,
if you can describe the problem as well as the customer,
or even better than them, they'll just assume
that you have the solution.
That's awesome. You ever been in that situation?
Isn't that a good one? Yeah.
Like, especially, you know, going back to the,
the health example too.
You ever had someone say, oh,
I know exactly what's going on.
Yeah, it's this, this, and this,
and they articulate it in a way that is totally true,
but better than you articulated it.
And it can be any sort of problem.
And when that happens, like it's just natural to assume,
like, you wouldn't think that someone would describe it
that way and then go, oh, but I have
no idea what to do about that.
Like, it doesn't happen, right?
Like, usually someone describes it that well,
and they can, they can point you
in the right direction at least.
So, like, just this, this first light bulb alone,
even though it's only, you know, one fifth
of this whole thing, uh, it can put a, a major dent in your,
uh, persuasive job that you have to do with this one alone.
For sure. I wanted to add something to that.
'cause you mentioned like if someone can describe the pain,
you know, super well, um, I've always found like
anything that I've personally gone through,
I can identify the pain really, really well, right?
Um, and that's why I always felt like with my businesses,
I've always kind of started from a place
of personal experience.
Um, because I know if I've experienced that level
of frustration or pain that'll resonate with somebody else.
And so I just kind of look at myself first
and what problems I've experienced.
Um, and anytime I'm like studying like a new niche where I,
I don't know, like skincare for women,
you know, like I don't, right?
That's not really a problem for me.
But there have been moments in time
where let's say I do get pimples
or, you know, I start to really tap into
that empathy from my personal experience
and then start to look into
what other people are experiencing
and trying to establish that like wholesome connection that,
you know, I think, um, yeah, I think that's the key.
You said empathy in the beginning, so I just wanted to share
that wholesome connection.
Yeah, I like that phrase a lot.
Yeah, listening is often more effective
for persuasion than speaking.
Uh, funny enough, because if you don't really dive in and,
because you're right, like if
it's something like skincare, I don't know.
And, and anything I would write
or that I would get from Chad GPT would be so superficial.
You really have to speak to people.
You really have to listen and hear how they describe things
because there's gonna be a lot of nuance in it.
And in copywriting, the money's in the nuance.
All right, awesome job gang. Yes. That's light bulb one.
Let's go into light bulb two now.
Uh, but first lemme show you an example
of light bulb one copy, fair warning.
John knows this. Ross knows this.
Once you see the light bulbs, you can't unsee them.
So you're going to, you're gonna see them everywhere.
Billboards, TV, commercials, of course,
social media, everywhere.
Um, so it's good to get some practice with it.
And, uh, at the end we'll play a fun game.
We should have time to play a little guess the light bulb.
We're all showing ad. And then you type in the
chat the number of the light bulb.
That's always cool. But here's one
so you can start to get a feel for it.
So this is from a, uh, a psychiatrist
who took our accelerator.
K he helps people with, uh, wandering mind.
He calls it a DHD and such.
So from scattered to focus,
and this is a light bulb, one copy
for many feeling scattered is a regular occurrence.
Not only do they struggle to get on top of their work,
they can barely get on top of the moment.
Do I wash the dishes? Do I write that report?
Do I get a snack? Maybe I'll just watch
something for a few minutes.
I see heads nodding here, this is me too gang.
By the way, I think a lot of us are like this.
Meanwhile, they try multiple laps, systems
and techniques without success.
Each one collapsing under the last.
So he is someone, he's a very empathetic person.
Like I said, he's a psychiatrist,
like he's not a professional marketer by any means,
but he does very well 'cause he knows his customer so well
and really realizes heavily on light bulb one.
Uh, do you feel the empathy in this writing, by the way?
Like, can you tell like this guy, like really caress
and really gets his person?
Totally. Okay,
let's move on to light bulb two.
So the symbolism of the, the characters here,
I promised you, so the bear, first of all, going back to
what I was saying about not manipulating your customer,
if I want to do that, I would've made this animal
a rabbit, right?
You're, you're small, you're weak, you need me,
you can't survive on your own,
but I didn't, you wanna treat
your customer as if they're strong.
Uh, David Ogilvy said this famous David Ogilvy, mad Men,
David Ogilvy, uh, your customer is intelligent.
Treat them like they're smart, capable, strong.
So that's why it's a bear.
But also the bear is very close to the ground.
Uh, have you had someone, a customer come to you
and they think that they're, that they're the first one
to experience their problem?
That always happens, right?
Because they're in the thick of it.
So that's why you, the, the entrepreneur, the company,
the person selling the product, you're are,
you are the, the owl.
You fly above. You have this benefit of perspective.
You've seen it all before.
So like Uncle Ben says in Spider-Man, with great power,
which you have because of your sight,
your vision comes great responsibility
and you wanna use that wisely.
So a little bit of symbolism behind the characters there.
That's why I went with those.
But this is my favorite illustration.
'cause you can see the whole scene here from the light bulb
one side to the lipo five side and all the bridges.
So we have your bridge in the middle here, this very nice,
strong, well constructed bridge.
Uh, but also these dilapidated ones, these broken bridges.
And that's what light bulb two represents.
It's the other bridges that your customer has either tried
in the past, is currently considering right now,
or is being tempted by.
So you might imagine for those broken bridges
that there's an advertiser behind those trying
to get your customer to take those bridges.
And it would be wrong to not give voice to those things.
So again, you want to give voice to these light bulbs.
And we tend to wanna ignore this, right?
We're like, nah, we're the only game in town.
I don't wanna speak to my competitors.
I don't wanna give them any publicity or anything.
Um, one, that doesn't mean
that you need to actually name them.
You could, and a lot of people do.
I'll show you some examples of that.
Um, but you at least want to talk about the criteria, right?
And that's a big thing
with the five light bulbs is doing this honestly,
where you're not just throwing rocks at your, your enemies
or your competitors and saying, ah, they suck.
Like, you wanna make a good rhetorical argument
and say like, look, here's the buying criteria.
Here's how you consider your,
you should consider your different options
and we check all these boxes
and that's why we think we are the best solution for you.
Those other bridges don't check these boxes.
That's why we don't, we don't think
that they're the best solution for you.
Does that make sense? Totally. Make strong, strong good.
Make strong, honest, persuasive arguments,
not just like childish bashing of your competitors.
'cause remember, your customers
smart and they can see through that stuff.
Lemme give you, tell you what,
lemme give you the example, right, right now.
'cause I got this up here. So here's a good light bulb to,
you can see, remember what I said earlier?
Platform agnostic. So here's an Instagram post.
This is an an Instagram ad. I see this ad everywhere.
I dunno if you guys see this. It must be spending a lot
storyteller tactics, uh, great light bulb to ad.
So notice they're comparing
storyteller tactics, uh, pip deck.
It's also called two books.
So the, the books would be those broken bridges.
And they're saying, Hey, those
aren't getting you what you want.
Remember, they don't check the boxes that you need.
Our product does check those boxes.
So good example right here of a light bulb two add.
Now let's dive into this for you.
Let's figure out your light bulb twos.
So draw a light bulb two. And this is a side view.
So unlike the the angled shot,
we can't see all those bridges.
So they're, they're in the distance here,
so you can just put it on the edge of the cliff.
And then light bulb two represents
other options They've tried, your customers tried.
All right, so, uh, I'll play that music again.
Take a couple minutes and get down a few ideas
for your light bulb too.
What have they tried or considering or are being tempted by?
And I'll type that in the chat as well.
All right, you got some good ideas, Dan,
By the way, people, uh, oh, by the way,
send me pictures of what you're drawing.
I always ask for those and I get some awesome ones.
I also get some terrible ones and I love those too
because mine are always terrible.
Uh, so please, lemme put my email in the chat and, uh,
and send those over to me.
Uh, people like to have a lot of fun with light bulb too.
So one thing you can do is like, like when they, when
that bear falls down the chasm, what is waiting
for your customer down there?
So you might draw some water down here.
Uh, we, I, I get things like piranhas and alligators
and sharks and all this stuff.
Dragon, there was a dragon one time.
So, uh, yeah, so have some fun with this.
I, you know, marketing is typically
not a lot of fun for people.
I think you guys probably like it more than most people, uh,
which makes me happy to be here.
Uh, but still it can be a grind.
So that's why I'm, I'm telling you, bring colored pencils,
draw dragons, and just lighten it up.
Okay, so that was light bulb two.
Uh, oh, we already got one in there. Awesome.
Thanks for sharing, Chan. Lemme pull that up.
Yeah, great job, Chan. Very cool.
You got the, you got the icons in there. Awesome.
Rocking it. Yeah. Uh, I, I can tell you that too.
You know, red reason why it's red light bulb,
one red, right?
The bad place fiery don't want to be there anymore.
That's why light bulb one is red.
The problem area, uh, light bulb, two reason why
that's yellow is I think of
a banana and slipping on a banana.
And like, that's a misstep.
So that's why I made that one yellow.
And then, uh, I'll,
I'll tell you the other ones when we get to 'em.
Uh, so let's hop into light bulb three
here, which is our next one.
This is my favorite. And again, in this book, this concept
for light bulb three really came from this book.
I think it's the most powerful thing in this book.
And it's Eugene Schwartz's idea of the mechanism.
And what he found was when markets get really saturated,
there is a pattern, there's a pattern of success in
what happens when markets get really saturated.
Uh, and by the way, this is back in the fifties.
So like, if what he found worked then like,
or is was needed back then,
of course it's needed now, right?
'cause he was complaining about things being saturated in
the fifties, pre-internet.
Um, so pay attention to this one.
So what he found was that, uh,
what happens when a market gets saturated is that
everyone's making promises, right?
Like promise, promise, promise,
light bulb five, that that's promise.
So make more money, lose more weight, et cetera.
But when everyone's saying that you don't stand out,
everyone's just saying the same thing.
So what he found was that the people
who were successful were the ones who
shifted their messaging from the promise
that is lip bulb five to how the promise is achieved.
That is lip bulb three.
And he called that
how the promise is achieved, the mechanism.
Have you guys heard this term before?
It, it's fairly well known in copywriting circles.
The mechanism sometimes called the unique mechanism,
and I call it light bulb three.
Okay? So this is your, uh, this is your approach.
This is your philosophy.
And in, in the info world,
you typically hear terms like formula,
signature system blueprint.
In the physical product world,
this might be your technology.
So if it's a pair of sneakers,
it might be the shock absorbers that are in the,
in those sneakers, it might be Under Armour.
And the fabric that is used,
and you'll see this, like, you'll see this in ads,
you'll see like there'll usually be a registered trademark
for whatever that technology is for the Under Armour.
Um, lemme show you an example of this.
This is, um, 'cause again,
this is what's so cool about this.
All these different industries and types of products.
This is for software. So, uh, so we use this in my home.
It's, it's called you Need a Budget, YN
and they have a software product.
But why they have done so well is
that they don't just sell their features alone.
Like, because you, you can copy those,
their competitors can easily copy the budgeting feature
and like creating a report
of your monthly spending, that's easy to copy.
What's tough to copy is their four rules.
So they have these four rules.
It's their philosophy of budgeting, give every dollar a job,
save for a rainy day, roll with the punches
and live on last month's income.
Okay? So do you see how that's different than
just software features?
It's the thing that drives their software features. Okay?
So this is their mechanism and,
and they built online courses around this.
They have a podcast around these four rules.
So they're much bigger than just a software company.
And the cool thing is you can apply these lessons to,
to really any, any type of product.
So let's do this now. Light bulb three.
So oops, so draw a light bulb.
Now we're gonna draw our bridge. So this, this is now
where we get to your bridge.
Uh, I'll make it red.
Use whatever color you want
and you can do like an Indiana Jones jungle style bridge
or more like a Roman stone bridge, whatever you want.
But draw your bridge and then
put your light bulb three over it.
And this is again, your
lip three is your approach, your approach, your mechanism,
your philosophy, your system,
all different words to say the same thing.
Uh, any questions about this before we go on?
And, um, before you get into workshop,
and this one, this one tends to be the most confusing.
John, this one making sense. Have you heard of this,
this mechanism idea from Schwartz?
I've heard the unique mechanism. Yeah.
Um, yeah, what's your, yeah, this is, this is perfect.
This is the one that I, I feel like for me,
needs more clarification.
So I'm excited to just kind of dive into it. Cool.
Let's do that. Yeah, so let's dive right in. Guess, yeah.
So get a, a, a few bullets down.
Some ideas for not your product,
but the underlying philosophy behind your product.
Uh, and, and if you don't have one,
you might look at some competitors
and that will give you an idea of maybe
where you can find a gap.
All right, let's get into it.
All right? Yeah, I hear you spark.
It's easy to confuse this one with the features. Yeah.
Now the features can have their own sort
of light bulb three within them,
but we're talking about a more
overarching light bulb three here.
And, uh, yeah. And a lot of products
or people, service providers, doesn't matter.
Just don't really have this.
So it's a good thing to be aware of,
and you don't have to have that super fancy name
or that patented technology right away,
but at least take the first step
and try to document what you do have.
And that gives you something to improve upon.
Uh, Asim says, I guess the features are more general
and this is something unique about you.
Yeah, exactly. Unique.
Uh, your USP might think about it that way.
I think when it comes to features, why a,
that software company is a great example where
their underlying philosophy drives their features.
Like the fact that they have, one of their rules is to,
to roll with the punches financially.
They have a feature that helps you with that.
It helps you shift money around.
So in case you get blindsided by a bill,
you can easily shift money from one budget to another.
So do you see how the, like that's a good example.
Do you see how their philosophy, you can connect the dots
between that and their features, whereas a lot
of products have features
that really don't have an underlying philosophy.
So if you can do this, it's, it's not easy.
This is the hardest one, but it's also the most potent one.
This is really interesting. I, I think this is one
of those things that I've noticed in the, in the field,
you know, just as a consumer seeing ads, right?
It's always like steal my, my so
and so media buying blueprint that has generated me tens
of millions of hundreds of millions
of dollars using this exact four step formula.
Um, you know what I mean?
It's like a very specific approach, um, which is just kind
of a way of like creating that intrigue,
but then you look at it, you're like,
oh, you're just doing that.
Like, yeah, but, but it is that intrigue for sure
because it's like, oh, it's a proprietary method that you,
oh, like for example, uh, a course that I took was like,
it was called, it was like using the scroll
frame optimization.
Um, it was like something he had made up,
but it made a lot of sense, um, of like
how to optimize your ads.
And I think this is definitely something I probably missed
on my end in, in, in like promoting my own services,
actually, like in my agency.
Um, because it's like, it's, it's a good way to kind of
systemize your process
and make it look different than any other, uh,
service out there or product.
And, um, I think for me, this, my light bulb went off
of like, okay, what do I do differently in my business
that you said, like that I can tie my own values to, um,
and make it unique that no one really can like steal,
even if it's not proprietary technology.
It's like, no, we stand behind this method of, of,
of running ads and we don't settle for anything else.
Like, and this is our way of doing that.
Like, if that makes any sense. Totally. Yeah.
And, and, uh, and I've seen like a lot of those, yeah, like,
like sparse was saying, steal my
framework, steal my blueprint.
And then you buy the thing and you're
like, oh, that's just what you're doing.
Um, I'm, I'm a big fan of making this public. Mm-Hmm.
And then, and you know, shouting about it from the rooftops
and standing behind it, I mean, to get metaphor a second,
the five light bulbs is my light bulbs three.
And look, I'm, I'm giving the thing away.
It's on the website. I, uh,
I don't give you four light bulbs and sell the fifth one.
I'm like, right. This is why I think this is the best.
Uh, and yet I'm still able to sell like $5,000 programs
around it too, right?
So, um, so I'm all about making this thing public
and like, just like putting a bunch of, like,
making a good argument for it.
Really love it. Um, yeah.
And you know, the, and the best way
to like learn light bulb threes is
to study other light bulb threes from other companies
and industries and everything.
Uh, and I have for you guys, lemme pop this in now,
in case any of you have to drop off earlier,
but I have a swipe file for you.
So if you enter your info into that,
I'll send you a swipe file.
And there's, um, I'll show you some more too at the end
of this when we play guest the light bulb.
So those are in there, plus I got some other ones too.
And that'll help you, help you learn some light bulb
threes amazing.
All right, gang. Um, we need to go pretty quick here.
Uh, we're, we have an hour, right, John?
We do, we have 15 minutes left.
And if you, I mean, I can stay until 1130.
So that's, that's up to anybody if,
if you're on a time crunch, well, I, I wanna let,
let's try to wrap it up in an hour.
'cause uh, uh, in case people blocked off only an hour,
I wanna make sure that they can finish it.
So tell you what, we'll go pretty quick.
Let's do lipo four really quick.
Uh, we won't do silent work time
for this one 'cause this is just your offer.
So let me show it to you
and then we'll just move on to lipo five.
Oops, shared the wrong thing. Here we go.
So this is the action step,
and that's why you see lip bulb four here,
the bear taking this step.
So it's like, okay, lipo one, I understand company
or seller entrepreneur, that, that you get me.
I understand that those options
aren't the best options for me.
Lip bulb two, I like your approach.
I believe in your approach.
You make a good argument for your approach. Like Pope three.
Okay, now how much money is it? Okay, that's a good deal.
My value, the value I'm gonna get from this is much more
than the price that you're charging,
therefore, I'll take this step with you.
Mm-Hmm. So this is, this is the, the action step right here.
So here's an example of this,
and you probably recognize this kind of language.
Light bulb four language. This is an old ad.
This is, do you make these mistakes in English?
One of the ones that if you study copywriting
that they're gonna make you hand copy
and, uh, look the coupon, right?
The dotted line here, like
that should signal light bulb four.
And you see this on product pages today, sales pages.
It's, it's where you see risk reversal, the guarantee,
the pricing plan, all that.
That's all light bulb four.
So go ahead and, um, just draw that here.
Draw a little light bulb there.
I'll just write your offer. So go back later.
If you wanna flesh this out, you probably know this already,
what your offer is, name of the product, price
of the product, any risk reversal, like a guarantee,
pricing terms, kind of boilerplate stuff.
Okay? Okay. So let's do lipo five now.
So this is the other side of the bridge.
So let's go back and look at that one again.
There's lipo four, the coupon.
You can think about that as lipo four language, which
by the way, a lot of people, we call this getting stuck in
the lipo four silo.
And maybe you've done this where you've seen this
before where it's just all lipo four language,
like just all about the features
and the offer and everything.
And of course you need that.
But what a lot of people tell me
after seeing the five light bulbs is, oh man,
that now I have a lot of other stuff to talk about.
And you'll find that by giving voice
to these other light bulbs, you actually get more attention
and more action on your light bulb before.
Okay? So light bulb five, you can see the bear cheering here
and the birds are chirping,
the sun is shining, the sky is blue.
So you wanna paint a pleasing picture
of that other side of the bridge.
And again, you wanna give voice to this,
you don't want to just assume it.
And, uh, and here's a good example of this.
I, I love these old magazines like Reader's Digest and Life
and such, and a lot of good ads in there.
And especially for light bulb,
five travel ads are a good one to use for inspiration.
'cause they're really painting that picture, right?
When you do a travel ad,
you just show pretty pictures of where they're gonna travel to.
So, so here's a good light bulb five ad.
Have you seen the other side of Hawaii? The big island?
And so even if you're not in the travel industry, try
to apply this to your product.
Like paint that pleasing picture for them.
Where are they going to go? Where are they going
to jettison off to?
Uh, and when you do that, when you paint
that pleasing picture, then, then that's when you really,
to go back to the beginning here,
when you paint that picture of light bulb one
and you paint this picture of light bulb
five, what does that create?
It it creates tension. That's the before and after.
And what does tension seek? It?
It seeks release or resolution,
which is another way to say action.
And that's what we want from our customers, right?
We want them to take that action
of walking across the bridge.
So it becomes this cool formula, uh, where if you give voice
to lipo one and you give voice to lipo five,
and then you show how you can connect those dots
between them and gain that trust, you're gonna get
that tension and then release,
which is someone buying from you, which is what we all want.
Love that. Cool. So just to wrap up, gang.
Yeah, go ahead. And
lip oh five is your customer's new life.
That's what we call it. Because
after success with your product,
even if it's only in a small way, they do have a new life,
a new and improved life.
I mentioned something. Go for it.
Uh, yeah, I feel like in my early days of marketing,
it was like light bulb one
and five were like the most common ones
that you would talk about.
It would be like pain points and testimonials.
That's like, um, the two light bulbs that I think a lot
of the, the space talks about
and a lot of the times you see in marketing.
Um, but you're being to see a lot more of number two.
But I feel like three, three is, is one of those things
that are less talked about.
Um, but yeah, when you think te I, when I think
of testimonials, I think of of like both from number five.
Yeah. The, the, the cool thing and,
and Rosten has seen this in the course is that, well,
what we do is we, so we create what's called a messaging map
where we, it's essentially a soup version of
what you guys are creating right now
where we really fill out these five columns
and we'll put testimonials under each of the columns.
So a testimonial to me and
or to us in lip bulb five world is just a light bulb
four quote.
You get that? So it's just a light bulb four quote.
'cause it's a, so what someone says about your lip bulb
four, which is just your product Mm-Hmm.
At the same time we get quotes about our light bulb three.
So why nap? You need a budget.
They, they, they have this on their website
where they're like, man, I just love the four rules, right?
They're not saying I love the software, right?
They're saying, I love the four rules, the methodology.
And when you have quotes for each of the light bulbs,
like you build this, really, these messaging maps we create
are just like killer.
That makes sense. So you're, you're, you're,
you're taking like a, a general testimonial
and then you're identifying what they're saying
and then whatever they say you place under a certain light
bulb and there's test they Yeah.
So testimonials themselves have their own
categories what's been said.
Yeah. What's being said in the testimonial. Yeah.
We don't even really call 'em testimonials.
Uh, it's a voice of customer, voice of customer.
If it's, if it's, if it's a light bulb for voice
of customer, then it'll be yeah.
A product testimonial. Uh, so absolutely. Yeah.
And it becomes a language. I mean, you, you,
you've heard me speaking it here.
This is a great light bulb one ad. Yeah.
We'll use it the same way, you know,
we'll hear a hear someone say something
and go, oh man,
they just gave us a great light bulb two quote,
and then that boom that goes into the messaging map.
Can, can I say one thing about that?
'cause I, I just got another light bulb in my head
and I love using that, that analogy, but, um, totally,
but using that
to support your arguments when you're making ads.
Um, so if you're editing a video
and I think as an exercise, identifying
what the light bulbs are in your own ads, um, if you can,
if you can find a voice of a customer, let's say
after you talk about the customer's pain points
or talk about your approach
and you fill it in with another voice of customer
or testimonial right afterwards, it like
cements it even further.
Um, and same thing with like landing pages,
but I know not a lot of people here are doing landing pages,
but it kind of follows that same sequence.
And if you can make it as logical as possible,
then I think it, you know,
your message becomes that much stronger.
Yeah, exactly. It, it's um, it's copywriting best practices.
You make a claim and you back it up with proof
and that applies, uh, to all the light bulbs.
So yeah, absolutely. Right.
Uh, let's play,
because we only got five minutes, let's play some guess the
light bulb here, gang, since I promised you that.
So go ahead and type in into the chat the number
that you think this ad is showing.
Which light bulb number. Okay, so a gum road alternative
that helps you grow your business.
This is for Podia, this is website software.
What light bulb is this? The word alternative?
There's really two in here,
but I'm really looking at that word alternative.
No, sparse. Got it. Yeah. Two light bulb, two right?
Alternative alternative bridges. Yeah.
And then, but grow your business.
That is light bulb five language. So, and that's that.
You'll see that with the light bulbs.
They're like ingredients. You, you can
use 'em in these different recipes.
Okay, this is from Ramit Seti, uh, very good marketer.
I was tired of feeling awkward.
Only one light bulb in that one, but which one is that?
Yeah, there we go.
And John, that's what we're talking about.
That's a light bulb. One testimonial voice
of a customer quote.
So great. So he took, so yeah,
so you can use a light bulb one quote as a headline and,
and have it work very well.
100%. I love that. Yeah. Nice, nice job gang.
So yeah, light bulb one.
Uh, so this is a Facebook ad
for you probably heard of on it.
Big supplement company, alpha Brain.
And then look at that registered trademark
that should signal which lip bulb this is.
Black label is the ultimate breaking glass,
break glass in case of emergency must get stuff done.
Now, formula, that word formula is another signal as
to the lip bulb and yeah, you guys got it.
Lip bulb three. Now what's this down here?
Limited time, 20% off. What lip bulb is that?
Or yes, par. Yeah, so you see the difference
and you see how if you get stuck in
that light bulb four silo, it just becomes kind of boring.
Just like all about the
discount and the pricing and all that.
Um, compared to the, like, this is very rich.
This, this language and this idea, this concept.
There's also a lot of light bulbs happening in there, right?
Like it's, it's filled with persuasive.
They use a lot in here. Yeah. Mm-Hmm.
Yeah, there's a lot of lip bulb five in here.
These are all lip bulb five.
Yeah, this is, um, this one is in that swipe file.
This is a good one to study.
Uh, okay, so how about this one? This one's a little tricky.
So the travel wallet by Bellroy.
So it's, it's the wallet right here.
The smaller one, uh, smaller, slimmer, smarter.
Yeah. Five, five. I would say five and two.
'cause you got the comparison going on,
but then the comparison is showing you the benefits, right?
So a little bit of both.
It's, it's kinda like that ad that I show
with the check boxes, isn't it?
The side by side thing. Um,
but there's these benefits that go along with that.
Could this be a three?
Uh, this one's a little harder to, yeah.
You know, they all, they all kind of melded together.
Uh, yeah, they can make it more of a three.
If it was something about like how they,
how they made it small or like,
because there might be a drawback
to making it smaller, right?
It's like, oh, well it can fit less.
So maybe they had some technology
where like there's like a foldout compartment
and it's like, I see it can actually fit twice
as much in half the size.
That would make it a little bit more of a, a light bulb.
Three. That makes sense. Ross, you have weight loss.
Yeah, you could use the same, same copy for it.
Weight loss ad. Okay,
so I think this is the last one.
Yeah, last one. So we take, this is growth sprints.
We take SaaS companies from 10 million to a hundred million
annual recurring revenue.
Well, light bulb or light bulbs are in this one.
Yeah. Yeah. Five is the big one, right?
It's really looking forward. But there's also some
one in here too, right?
Like, it, it mean it's very, it's very quantitative.
It's just numbers, right? There's not a lot
of emotion in this, but the
10 million is where they are now.
Light bulb one, two,
where they wanna be, which is a hundred million.
And then look at this, what light bulb was in this first
line here using our SaaS growth sprint
framework three.
It's a good example of a few light bulbs
in the same recipe here.
And that's all I got for you gang.
So yeah, I'll type that link in the chat again,
if you wanna get these ads and some other ones,
we got a cool swipe file for you.
But, um, mostly just wanna thank you for having me here
and hope that was helpful.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
Billy, do you have time for questions?
Yeah, I can stick around. No problem. Okay.
Does anybody have any questions for Billy?
And first off, just thank you for your, your wisdom.
Um, really appreciate that in depth overview.
Uh, for those who, who who've seen who are seeing this
for the first time, you know, this, this light bulb
number three approach.
This is, yeah, this is number three. My life is very meta.
Um, I hope you guys can apply this in your creative work
and your marketing and your copywriting,
and you can start to identify
where in your marketing strategy
and mix you're missing some of these light bulbs
and how you can start to extract, um, those light bulbs, uh,
and, and put 'em into your, in your, into your content.
Uh, one of the things that I've, I've done when looking at,
uh, well, understanding all the light bulbs is like, okay,
if you look at someone's Facebook ads, for example,
and you look at their Facebook ad library, you'll see
that maybe they're only running like four ads,
and all of those are one in five light bulbs.
You're gonna see if you come in there as a,
a creative strategist, as a video editor, as a marketer,
you're gonna identify opportunities
and gaps in their own messaging
and their marketing, which allows you
to increase your own value
because you're coming in with problem solution, right?
Here, I noticed you only have four ads.
You could be, you're missing out on so many customers
because you're not identifying these needs
and these comparisons
and you know, you're,
you don't have this unique approach, right?
So you come in as an expert and when brands
and businesses hear this,
they're immediately like, how much does it cost?
Right? Mm-Hmm.
Um, and that's one of the things I've learned, uh,
even in my, in how I pitch, um, my video services and,
and ads to, to clients is like, I, I always audit their ads
and I'm like, you know, you guys could be doing a lot more.
Um, and here's what it's gonna take to make it happen.
So for anybody who's doing freelance work,
I would highly suggest adopting this, really mastering it,
and then even creating your own,
even if you do jump on calls
or so, like, like what Billy had in terms of examples,
be like, okay, here's what we're, we're like,
you can create a formula of, okay, we're gonna implement,
you know, six of these ads or whatever,
and have a template, so to speak,
and then charge a price for that
because that itself becomes a service
or an offering that's a very unique to you.
And, um, I honestly, I, I, I,
I know nobody's taking advantage of that.
So that's something you guys
can apply in your own businesses.
But yeah. Anybody have questions? Totally. Yeah.
Well, I mean, just to follow up on that. Yeah.
And one of the things we're doing now is it's,
it's in the very early stages,
but we have a licensed partner program.
Um, because I can only help so many people with this and,
and, and I try to stay in my lane in terms
of industries that I work in.
And there's so many industries. I mean, this is,
it's a messaging framework, right?
I can, I can apply to anything.
Um, so we have a few people on board now who are licensed
to use the five light bulbs.
And so I, I help them implement this with their clients,
give 'em all the, our worksheets
training and everything like that.
So, um, if you're interested in that,
we're not taking anyone right now,
because again, it's in the early days, but, um,
but reach out and, uh, so at least it's on my radar
and, um, we can discuss it later.
Um, but, um, but yeah, to answer, there's,
there's a question kind of related to,
in the chat from Chan, my first job as a marketer, I,
yeah, that really led me to, to where I am now, where I left
that job in the engineering world.
And then I was running my beer site,
my home brewing website,
and got involved in online communities,
online marketing communities.
Uh, copy blogger was a big one that, that was involved
with back in the day.
Brian Clark over copy, blogger, and, uh, and,
and so I started, um, there were other businesses in there,
obviously, and I started to give them ideas
'cause I studied copywriting and marketing.
And even though they were bigger than me, I would say, Hey,
if you just do this, if you tweak
this, I think it would really help.
And it worked. And they were like, Hey,
can you help me some more?
So eventually that became my full-time thing.
Uh, I was getting tired of the beer website anyways,
and I wound up selling that
and going full-time into what I do now, which is
consulting copywriting,
and in the past few years, more teaching.
Uh, no problem. I hope that answered.
I I think we have a couple more questions here. Sparse.
Uh, where do you draw the line between the need
for persuasive copy with transparency and authenticity?
Yeah, I, I think the, the,
the most persuasive copy is the most transparent copy
and the most honest copy.
Uh, Joe Sugarman talks about this famous Joe Sugarman
copywriter developed blue blocker sunglasses.
And he says that, uh, he has a book called Triggers,
and it's like these persuasive triggers.
And he says that honesty is the most, um,
the most powerful one.
And like, real honesty, not like fake honesty.
And so, yeah, that's, that's how I look at it, is, uh,
the more honest and vulnerable
and transparent you can be, the more you will benefit
in your, in your success.
And, and that's easier said than done.
You know, a lot of people think like
honesty means like, well, don't like tell lies
or exaggerate your product and all that.
And yeah. Like, it's definitely that.
But it's more than that too. Like, I, I tell my clients
who are like, a lot of 'em are like,
they are the, the face of their business.
They're coaches, they're service providers, course creators.
And I'm like, yeah, like, you're not lying,
but you're also not really opening up and being yourself
and telling your whole story and being vulnerable
and all that stuff, so you're not really being honest.
And when and when they do that, when they start, like,
'cause a lot of 'em, they, like, they, a lot
of 'em are very professional too,
and they run in those circles, professional circles.
So it's not really accepted
or it's maybe a little taboo to like tell a vulnerable
personal story, but without fail when they do that,
their business grows.
Love that. I have a question for you.
Um, so for have a lot of like freelancers in here, um,
a lot of like just independent, uh, creators
and creatives here, what advice would you give them, um,
in terms of like leveling them,
leveling up their like income and opportunity?
Like, what would you suggest? 'cause you kind of went, you,
you worked in, you know, you, you were working under the man
and now Mm-Hmm.
You kind of went and drifted off on your own and,
and what, what advice would you give?
Yeah, I would say the biggest word is, uh, relationships.
And so, yeah, so form relationships, uh, I,
despite being like an online marketing guy, I,
I love going to conferences.
It's amazing how much easier it is
to get work at a conference than running a Facebook ad.
I mean, I, I remember, I, I was at a conference
with a buddy, uh, and, um, he, he was doing like, yeah, and,
and he, he was doing Facebook ads.
Uh, that was his job. And we got into an elevator
after one of the sessions, the, uh, uh, a speaker was done,
got into an elevator, and there was a woman
who got into it, and everyone knew who she was.
She has a pretty big business.
And, uh, and my friend and her were talking and,
and she said, oh, what do you do?
And he said, oh, I, I, I do Facebook ads.
She's like, oh my gosh, I need you. Here's my business card.
Please call me.
And it's like, imagine if he was trying to get her
as a client, if he was running his own Facebook ads
or doing online marketing, right?
How difficult that would be.
Um, so in person stuff, like being seen, uh, you know,
doing stuff over Zoom if you need to,
but I, I really like in person just
developing those relationships.
That's the, the best thing you can do
as a freelancer service provider.
And that, and that's how I've gotten the
vast majority of my clients.
It hasn't been from online marketing,
it's been from referrals, word of mouth,
keeping in touch with people.
Awesome. Yeah, I would, I would definitely agree to that.
I think the relationship aspect, it's all about trust
when you're, when you're a freelancer, when you're working,
uh, I would say in the services world, right?
Um, I think initially getting people in the door
and then, you know, if, whether you're using Upwork
or any type of like, freelancing type of platform,
but it, it, it's, it's retaining customers
and like building a relationship with them, I think is key.
At least the ones that you love working with.
Um, spar has another question.
What are some of your favorite tools
or resources you use to stay updated?
Hmm. I mean, I'm not as, as you heard,
I'm not a huge tool guy.
I try to keep things very simple.
Uh, I use Apple Notes for pretty much everything.
I, I've done a lot of work.
Does anyone know Tiago Forte at Building a Second Brain?
That's his business. And he is a,
a bestselling book out by the same name.
Uh, I've helped him a lot in growing his business.
And so, and, and I took his course initially
before I even met him and started working
with him and helping him.
So, um, so I'm definitely in the building a second Brain
productivity, those, those circles.
Uh, so yeah, and anything that they're into,
I'm probably into, but again, I'm not
huge on tools and software and all that.
Hey, John, can I add one to one thing?
Yeah, of course, brother. Hey, first of all,
I just wanna say thank you both for having this together,
this conversation for us.
I, I, I also wanted to offer something to the kind
of the editing community that one of the ways
that I've found, um, the lessons from the five light bulbs
and combining that with the ads Rx program is
with the Ads rx.
That was like the first time that I got hip to like,
the importance of like modular clips, right?
And through the, the five light bulbs I've started
to incorporate like, some of the, the, the content into some
of these like modular spaces, right?
So it's like, it, it can give us a, a,
a way to kind of like look at the content
that we're going through, right?
Mm-Hmm. So now, like when I'm organizing things, it's like,
okay, I could put it here, here, here.
So when it's time to like edit, um, an ad, for example,
when we put those in these like five light bulbs,
it's like a another way of thinking
and framing our content to like, make ads.
So I just wanted to kind of offer, um, how these two things,
even though these two kind
of platforms can kind of work together.
I love that so much, Ralston.
And I was just gonna say that, um, it, it, it adds,
just like we talked about the voice of the customer
narrowing down exactly what they're saying in terms
of which light bulb,
the same thing you can do with your assets.
Um, and I know we're all saying you, you have a lot
of testimonials, you have a lot of reactions, you have a lot
of, um, the author
or the, the, the, you know, the, the person
of the company is speaking about
all those become modular clips.
And we talk about modularity Billy
and our program of like taking, you know, a long piece
of footage and breaking them down into, I mean per, like,
they're basically light bulbs if you think about it.
You know, and those become your little Lego blocks
that you can assemble in any way,
but now you have a better tool of classifying your, your,
your footage and not just, they're not just pieces of like,
they're not just raws anymore.
Now they have a purpose and meaning. I love that. Yeah.
I'm so glad that you, you made that connection.
'cause that's, that's really what this is about.
It's like how can we, um, really just hone in
and just make things tighter, right?
It's like it's, we are creating processes
that haven't been made before.
We're making these connections that haven't been made
before for Yeah.
Love that Roston. Yeah.
Very smart use of the five light bulbs. Amazing.
Um, I'll open it up for one more question
and um, does anybody have one more for Billy?
You've been super helpful Billy,
really appreciate your time, man.
Um, again, where can people find you?
I know you dropped your email in here.
I'm sure people are gonna be really curious to reach out
and find more about the five light bulbs.
Yeah, the best way is, yeah, reach out, uh, grab
that swipe file and then you'll be on my email list
and uh, you know, get some follow-up emails.
There's also, um, uh, a a, an educational series in there
that goes through them in more depth, kinda like
what I did today, but even deeper.
And yeah, hit reply and say hello.
Just say, say that you, you came from John's crew
and uh, yeah, I mean we have courses and programs
and I consult on this stuff and everything
to help you breach the gap from this,
these worksheet answers to a finished sales page
or an ad or something.
Um, but even if you don't do any of those, uh,
I just want people speaking this language.
'cause it just makes marketing easier. Love it.
And again, like it's just, it's all for free out there,
so spread the word about it.
'cause we gotta a cool movement going on over here.
Without a doubt, man. We are huge advocates for it.
And we appreciate your wisdom, man.
Thank you so much, Billy. Thank you, John. Thanks everyone.
Take care. All right, see you guys.
Appreciate you guys being on call. Bye.
See you the next one.